You had your time, but it's over!
Look above you, morons!
Where are Eren and Christa?
It's no use!
If you don't turn yourselves in, every last
Scout we captured will get the noose!
I entrusted something to Commander Pyxis.
When it comes, I will only watch.
It's up to you to decide.
You... and them.
That sure is a lot of wagons.
What's going on?
You don't know?
Right now, all the heads of the
military are meeting inside the castle
to finally dismantle the Scout Regiment.
See?
There's the gallows for
hanging their commander.
I bet it's ongoing as we speak...
his final judgment.
If humanity loses the Scout Regiment,
that means humanity loses their spear.
When enemies close in, you guard not with a
shield, but a spear that eliminates the threat.
Suppose now, if this instant,
Wall Rose were to be breached...
The residents of Wall Rose would again
flee and take refuge in Wall Sina.
But the earlier evacuation left stockpiles
with no more than a few days at best.
In the blink of an eye, most of the residents
would be forced to fight for survival.
Wall Rose and Sina... Humanity would be split
in two factions and civil war would erupt.
Even if the wall was not breached, Wall Rose
is continually suffering a food shortage.
It may not be Titans that breach Wall Sina...
There's a chance the residents
of Wall Rose do it first.
Reclaim Wall Maria.
If humanity is to ever hope for
a future, that is the only way.
Are you implying that the Scouts
are needed for such a cause?
Our duty as Scouts has always been
to charge forth at the enemy.
Cowering away will not solve anything.
Or could it be... you have some sort
of secret plan to overcome this ordeal?
Erwin, I don't think you understand.
The reason you're here today is not
to discuss our future within the walls,
nor is it because of something
as simple as murder.
Clause Six, Charter of Humanity.
"Thou shall not prioritize one's own
gain over the longevity of humanity."
You're here for this grave offense.
Indeed. You've refused to hand
over Eren Jaeger multiple times.
In doing so, you've violated the Charter.
But Eren is vital for reclaiming Wall Maria!
That is not for the Scouts to decide!
Eren Jaeger is a Titan whose
powers are not understood!
Sheltering him within the walls
is a risk to humanity!
It's absurd for a single commander
to have control of him alone.
And yet, you stubbornly persisted
in some plan of yours.
Not only did you feign his abduction
and conceal Eren Jaeger...
...but you silenced Dimo Reeves
since he knew of your plans.
This is clearly treason.
It is not a stretch to say that
you're the threat to humanity.
Commander Pyxis.
Hmm?
The Garrison and Scout Regiments
both risk their lives on the front lines.
How are we to know that
you're not his comrade?
I'm quite disturbed that you believe
we would align ourselves with the Scouts.
Nothing is more senseless
than humans killing humans.
In this cramped world that we humans have,
one spark will engulf all in no time.
When it came time to defend Trost District,
that's what I told my soldiers
before sending many to their deaths.
If the Scout Regiment is that one spark,
it should be smothered at once.
After all, if the Titans do manage to break
the wall and find hardly anyone left inside...
...those poor Titans might go hungry.
Very well.
Allow us to discuss.
Your Majesty... May we?
Erwin... Is this how you want it to end?!
In the name of the King,
I will announce your judgment.
Erwin Smith.
For violating Clause Six of the Charter
of Humanity, you are sentenced to death.
Your execution will be carried out immediately.
Take him.
Is this what you wanted, Erwin?!
With this, you're...
Wall Rose...
...has been breached!
The Colossal Titan appeared out of nowhere!
Along with the Armored Titan, they broke
through both gates of Calaneth District!
Currently, refugees from the East
are flocking here for safety!
Establish a route for the evacuees!
Have all Garrison troops
converge and defend the East!
Get the evacuees safely to Wall Sina!
Everyone, hurry! Saving the
evacuees is our top priority!
--Sir!
--No!
Hmm?
Close up all of the gates to Wall Sina!
Don't let a single refugee inside!
Huh?!
B-But that's... all the Wall Rose residents.
Your command is to sit back and
watch as half of humanity dies?
It's just like he said earlier!
That's asking for civil war!
We can't let the government lose control!
If that happens, it's over!
B-But... That's only a mere possibility!
It's enough for that possibility to exist!
Our authority is and always will be absolute!
Now, get moving!
Shit...
To think the wall would be
breached at a time like this...
Though, there is a silver lining.
We've already found the power.
All that's left is to bide our time
until the vessel takes it.
That's right. There's no need to be
flustered by this little disaster.
As long as Wall Sina holds up, we'll be fine.
Yes, once Lord Reiss comes back...
Let's do it! Close the gates!
Wait!
It'll be too late if we wait!
Who gets to choose?
Who decides?
What are you doing?! Hurry it up!
It'll be treason if you don't!
I will not!
What?!
Hey...
I... am a human of Wall Rose!
I will not allow the gates to be closed!
You fool!
I will stand behind him.
Dhalis Zachary...
Are you surprised at all by
their reaction, Premier Zachary?
No... Not a bit.
Zachary, what's the meaning of this?!
That report just now was a false alarm.
Rest assured.
At the moment, there has been
no report of a Titan attack.
You bastards! What is this farce?!
If you want the mastermind, it's me.
Pyxis?!
It seems most of the Interior Police
are off somewhere or other.
I suppose that's quite fortunate.
What do you mean?!
Earlier, I declared to you that the Garrison
Regiment isn't aligned with the Scout Regiment.
But I did forget to mention one thing...
I'm not aligned with any of you, either.
While I do possess some of the
same feelings as Erwin here...
...I considered leaving things
up to your government
if that were the better choice
for the sake of humanity.
You are, after all, much wiser than us
when it comes to Titans and the walls.
Supposing you actually cared about
saving as many people as possible,
I would have been fine
sending Erwin to the gallows.
Of course, depending on your decision,
all of us were prepared to forfeit our heads.
However, the answer you've
given us is very clear!
We may be ignorant about the Titans
and their powers, but...
I daresay, we in our ignorance can save
far more people than you ever could!
Y-You're a fool! What do you think
undermining us will accomplish?!
The citizens will never listen to you!
They'll obey whatever the crown says!
The regional lords will have none of this!
It seems you don't quite understand.
This is no mere threat.
It's a coup d'état.
We've successfully restrained
the Interior Police!
Mmm.
The thing with soldiers, they'll obey
their superior officer over the king.
Especially when the king in question is a fraud.
We will put in place a new ruler of our own.
It can't be... They're actually...
Don't even think you can
get away with this hoax!
If that disaster had in fact happened...
The decision that all of you made violates
Clause Six of the Charter of Humanity.
Furthermore, is installing a fake king
to personally control and run the
government not punishable by death?
Shit! Wake up, dotard!
What? Time to eat?
Shut up, you useless oaf!
Erwin...
This is your victory.
Aren't you happy?
Nile.
Humanity has just begun down a new path...
One far more dangerous than before.
And there you have it.
The coup d'état was successful.
Premier Zachary has control of
the capital and administrative district.
For the time being, the nobility haven't rebelled.
What about the Boss Reeves incident?
We got a confession that proved
the charges unfounded.
His son Flegel really pulled through big time.
Don't you get it?!
The government doesn't give
a shit about saving any of us!
Face the truth now, because it'll be
too late when you're dead!
That's right! If Titans attack us again,
there'll be nothing left this time!
Not the company! Not our families!
Let's print the truth before that happens!
Just like it's written right there, it shows the
charges were bogus, they abused their power,
and that King Fritz was a total fake.
All our actions were justified self-defense.
In other words, we're free people now.
Woohoo!
No... This can't be...
Looks like the gamble paid off.
Yeah.
It wasn't just Erwin though.
The lone choices of many
managed to change the world.
And I managed to kill the
three people you loaned me.
I'm sorry.
The thing is, part of the Interior Police, their
leader, Eren, and Historia are somewhere else.
If we don't find them soon...
I may have a clue about that.
Let's get there and put an end to this battle.
"Underground Chapel"
"A sacred location where the royal family's power
has been passed down for generations. The walls
are composed of a naturally luminescent ore."
As a result of Erwin's actions,
it was declared that the current
regime would be ousted.
That announcement came immediately after
the military gained control of the
capital and administrative district.
And took place upon the gallows
constructed specifically for him.
That's right.
It's exactly how Premier Zachary
explained in the speech.
Understand that our goal
is not to establish military rule.
In place of Fritz, a new ruler will
come from the true royal family.
They will be the one responsible
for leading the people.
I understand that well enough,
but do you really think people will simply
accept a new ruler just like that?
There're a lot of citizens out
there who are very worried.
At this point, who do we trust?
As far as humanity's concerned, we should
have let the government do as they please.
Like Commander Pyxis was saying,
they've somehow devised a means
of keeping humanity alive until now.
Even if they watch as half of humanity dies,
it's better than us going extinct.
Should I have let Eren go, risked my comrade's
lives, given up both my life and my duty,
and entrusted it all to the government?
If humanity is more precious
than one single life...
Your duty is as painful as ever.
Dying seems a far easier option.
In that case, why didn't you do as you said?
That's...
Shall I tell you my reason?
For a long time, I've hated those bastards!
--Huh?
--They piss me off!
Those pompous pricks and pigs
who think they're important...
No... Maybe I actually liked them.
I've been dreaming for
this day to come for ages.
That is... Even if you hadn't done it, I would've
given it a shot before I kicked the bucket.
I couldn't care less if this coup d'état
is good or bad for humanity.
I'm quite the scoundrel, right?
But you're no different than me.
You didn't want to die.
Just like me, you prioritize yourself
over the fate of humanity.
I... must be very conceited to think that.
What's your reason?
Now it's your turn to answer.
I...
...have a dream.
One I've had since I was a child...
Hange.
You might know where they are?
Yeah, I'll explain.
Erwin gave me this Scout investigation
report regarding Lord Reiss' land.
Most of it has to do with an incident five
years ago that shook up the Reiss family.
Five years ago?
Right. On the day Wall Maria was breached.
I'll summarize the important
bits from the beginning.
As the lord of his territory, popular opinion
of Rod Reiss wasn't all that bad.
He had five children, and his eldest
daughter Frieda was a down-to-earth girl
that even the peasants adored.
But that night, five years ago, disaster struck.
With the world having plunged into pure chaos,
some bandits raided and set fire
to the only chapel around.
Unfortunately, that night, the entire
Reiss family was there praying together.
And so, the whole family, save for
the head of the house, Rod Reiss...
...was massacred that night by the bandits.
To top it off, this incident occurred
just a few days before Historia's mother
was killed by the Interior Police.
In other words, immediately after losing
his family, Rod Reiss sought out Historia.
There must be a reason he
and his lackeys are after Historia.
The same bloodline?
Is there some secret to their blood?
I don't know for sure yet.
But what really makes me curious is that
parts of the chapel were completely wrecked.
The chapel itself is stone. It would take
tons of time and effort to destroy it.
Bandits would take what they can
and make a quick escape.
Plus, the only one who saw those
bandits was Rod Reiss himself.
Soon after, he used his own
fortune to rebuild the chapel.
But why?
If you think about it, it's actually stranger
that there were no traces of Titans.
Even if I'm jumping to conclusions, something
this suspicious deserves us checking it out.
What the hell?!
Before the night is over,
we'll have soldiers all over Reiss' land.
Unfortunately, I doubt
he'll be waiting that long.
If we don't hurry and get there,
Eren may end up being eaten.
If a Titan eats a person who can change into
a Titan and thus inherits their powers...
If that's actually true...
When and how did Eren become a Titan,
and who did he eat to gain his powers?
Shit!
Historia?
To save Eren, Mikasa and the
others head for the Reiss chapel.
However, the captured Eren finds out...
...his father, Grisha's, unforgivable sin.
Next episode: "Sin."